[Music] I
[Música]
'm gonna call the terror of the ladies
voy a llamar al terror de las señoras
okay
vale
the new YouTube sensation
a la nueva sensación de youtube
Emilio Palacios Emilio Palacio wants to
emilio palacios emilio palacio quiere
tell us something he found out the other day
comentarnos algo que el otro día se
hello good afternoon Emilio or good
hola buenas tardes emilio o buenas
evening how were you doing it was a moment
noches que tal era un momento
what's going on
qué pasa
here now
aquí ahora
good afternoon what's up what's up what's up
buenas tardes qué pasa que te cuenta
we're here and he left me with the one who
estamos aquí y él me dejaste con el que
turn off his mouth yesterday it was not full well
apaguen la boca ayer fue no anda lleno
well it's that
bueno bueno
many times the head arrived
es que muchas veces llegó la cabeza
the head arrived at three thousand revolutions
llegó la cabeza a tres mil revoluciones
very fatá man and lee I hit
muy fatá tío y lee le di a
end string instead of shortening the
finalizar string en vez de acortar el
king and we are already respecting the schedules
rey y ya estamos respetando los horarios
and everything I'm not going to suffer this for dad
y demás no voy a sufrir esto para papá
20 minutes you understand for twenty-something
20 minutos me entiende para veintitantos
minutes that was already a live like it was
minutos eso ya era un directo como que
lost and already such is a next one okay
se perdió y ya tal es una siguiente vale
but today we are complying with the schedules
pero hoy estamos cumpliendo los horarios
very well you have
muy bien
amazed me I have you
me tienes asombrado os tengo contentos a
all happy those I have I get proud yes yes
todos esos tengo obtengo orgulloso sí sí
for king and you know that you have to
para rey y ya sabéis que tenéis que
bring me many toys there is a
traerme muchos juguetitos que hay una
Pinocchio figurine that are not from the
figurita de pinocho que no son de la vía
mete route that you have seen there on twitter and
mete que has visto por ahí por twitter y
suck-up a problem don't take out more
chupamedias un problema no saquéis más
doll
muñeco
they are going to have to have some partitions
van a tener que tienen algún tabiques
we are going to have to have some partition
vamos a tener que tener algún tabique
well in the days when something is in
bueno en los días en los que va algo en
the inkwell okay I think I found
el tintero vale yo creo que encontrado
the click Emilio let's see if I don't let's see if
el clic emilio a ver si no me a ver si
I wasn't wrong after so many
no me equivocaba ya después de tantos
days things on our feet but well yes it
días las cosas en los pies pero bueno sí
is
que es verdad que aquí lo la suerte que
true that here the luck that we have in our theme are two the luck that we have our theme are two that we can count on Emilio Palacio and that here in the community we also have our dear mm and that is an encyclopedia okay it is becoming a kind
vale se está convirtiendo en una especie
of encyclopedia of newspaper archives no and it
de enciclopedia de hemeroteca no y lo
has everything okay and I went to my
tiene todo vale y me he ido al twitter
me's twitter and evidently I found myself
de mi me y evidentemente me encontré a
clicking let's listen to it okay
poner clic lo vamos a escuchar vale
how opportune I
qué oportuno
update it
lo actualizo
that it hasn't come out or that it didn't
que no me ha salido o que no
specify the mattress the bed the
especificó el colchón la cama el
furniture
mobiliario
look when one marries another person
mira cuando uno se casa con otra persona
the article 128 that they tell you that they
el artículo 128 que te dicen que se
are basing themselves on I know that it seems very good to me
están basando sé que me parece muy bien
okay what it says it mentions an article
vale lo que habla menciona un artículo
but I didn't understand the number I tell you it is that it is that you will
pero no entendió el número yo te lo digo
see it is that  you know how
es que es que ya verás es que sabrás que
twisted
retorcida
well, the thing about the belongings, we already made that
bueno lo de los enseres ya lo dejamos
part clear, I think it
claro esa parte yo creo
talks about article 127 of the
que habla del artículo 127 del código
civil code and a clause in which it says
civil y de una cláusula en el que dice
that if the usufructuary marries
que si se casan el usufructuario
another person,
con otra persona
right of usufruct
derecho de usufructo
and I tell you that
y yo te dice que
if we talked about it in the video, in case
si lo hablamos en el vídeo que por si
someone hasn't seen it, well we have it, it has
alguien no lo ha visto bueno lo tenemos
already been uploaded to teles, to seo and to hub, I
ya ha subido en teles al seo y en hub yo
freed both channels the other day in the
liberen los dos canales el otro día en
middle she gave us a class here and
medio nos dio aquí una clase que
all they were missing was the blackboard, come on, it was
solamente les faltó la pizarra vamos era
brutal
brutal
today I also sent you the twitter,
hoy te mandado también el twitter
the last one, the
la última
last Goya measurement in the first one, the one
la última medición goya en la primera la
that provides the current article of the
que dispone el artículo vigente del
civil code as of January 8, 2001,
código civil a 8 de enero de 2001
the first one, okay,
la primera vale
yes,
sí
here the civil code has undergone
aquí el código civil ha sufrido
many revisions, of
muchísimas revisiones
course,
claro
let's go to January 8,
vamos a 8 de enero de
January 2001, she talks about 127, the
de enero de 2001 ella habla del 127 el
civil code and well, she's had bad
código civil y pues ha tenido mala
luck because article 127, if you have it, there's
suerte porque el artículo 127 si tienes
a little red one,
hay un rojito
you can read what it says below in red
puedes leer lo que pone abajo en rojo de
light on the same
luz en la misma página de la misma
page.  you put and in article 127
página pones y en el artículo 127
that is not that is not made it is not clear
ese no es ese no es hecha no es claro
okay it
vale
is one that says article 127 is the
es una que pone artículo 127 es el
next one that has 1
siguiente que tiene 1
are or Emilio
estén o emilio
articles in force in the civil code as of
artículos vigentes en el código civil a
January 8, 2021 of the filiation actions
8 de enero de 2021 de las acciones de
effectively I knew that 127
efectivamente yo sabía que el 127 no
could not be it could not be because the
podía ser no podía ser porque los
first the first articles of
primeros los primeros artículos los de
affiliation is the civil registry is the
la afiliación es el registro civil es el
issue of births to the goddesses
tema de los nacimientos a las diosas ya
since those were not certain if those were
que eso no eran seguros si esos eran
certain okay well 127 precisely
seguros vales pues el 127 precisamente
has had bad luck because from 127 to
ha tenido mala suerte porque de 127 a
130 if you read the paragraph cited red that good
130 si lees el párra citó rojo que buena
under what is so red and below it tells you
bajo lo que tan rojo y abajo te pone
articles from 127 to 130 are repealed
artículos del 127 a 130 son derogados
for those who do not know has been repealed to
para el que no sepa ha derogado de
achieve a law means to annul the
lograr una ley significa anular la
vulgar word Emilio yes yes but they speak
palabra vulgar emilio sí sí pero hablan
for section 2.1 of the
por el apartado 2.1 de la disposición
sole repealing provision of law 1/2007 of
derogatoria única de la ley 1/2007 de
January of civil proceedings the BOE
enero de enjuiciamiento civil el boe
published in the BOE on 8  of January
publicado en el boe el 8 de enero
valid until January 8, 2001,
vigencia hasta el 8 de enero del 2001
if I'm not mistaken, it seemed to me
esto si no me equivoco me dio
vulgarly, not like that for any mortal, it
vulgarmente no así para cualquier mortal
is that articles 127 to 130 have been
es que el artículo 127 al 130 los han
sucked
chupado
in that announcement after the BOE but they were
en ese anuncio tras el boe pero estaban
drugged, they were valid until
drogados eran vigentes hasta el 8 de
January 8, 2001 and from January 8, 2001,
enero de 2001 y del 8 de enero 2001
Pedro Carrasco died 15 days later, I
pedro carrasco murió 15 días después
think more or less,
creo más o menos
with which, apart from the fact that that article does
con lo cual aparte de que ese artículo
not say that, it is an article of affiliation
no dice eso es un artículo de filiación
that has nothing to do with it, okay,
que no tiene nada que ver con él vale
okay, what is the article
vale qué es lo que lo que es el artículo
in reality, well, I have not even seen it, but that
en realidad pues ni lo he visto pero ese
is not this one, more of affiliation, it has
no es este más de filiación no tiene
nothing to do with usufruct, adoptions
nada que ver con el usufructo adopciones
of affiliation, yes, of course, it already speaks of the fact that
de afiliación sí claro ya habla de que
the usufruct is annulled at the moment that they
el usufructo se anula en el momento que
marry another person, effectively,
se casan con otra persona efectivamente
the article is very strong, what they
el artículo es muy fuerte es que lo
found over the weekend while they were
encontrado por fin de semana mientras
making croquettes, they looked for articles
que hacían croquetas buscaron artículos
and for me, the same applies to a broken one as to
y yo lo mismo vale para un roto que para
an unstitched one,
un descosido
well, the civil code, I
pues el código civil
saw people, let's see, there are several
vi gente a ver hay varios códigos
civil codes this is the state civil code
civiles este es el código civil estatal
then there are autonomous communities that
luego hay comunidades autónomas que
have their own civil codes that
tienen sus propios códigos civiles que
are subsidiary to this one they are laws
son subsidiarios de éste son leyes
inferior to this one and if they don't contradict it
inferiores a este y si no lo contra
too then there are
también entonces hay comunidades
autonomous communities that then have their own
autónomas que luego tienen sus propias
laws and yes and some do have that
leyes y sí y algunas si tiene ese
article but the civil code is state
artículo pero el código civil es estatal
the one that is in force in Madrid is
el que es el que es vigente en madrid es
this one ok
éste
ok so if you go to the next one
vale vale entonces si vas al siguiente
you will see article 503 in red
verás el artículo 503 en rojito
and you go down a little further to the
y bajas un poquito más abajo al capítulo
first chapter of the a fruit because she
primero de los un fruto porque ella
talks about her she talks about that code
habla de ella habla de que el código
127 would apply
127 se aplicaría
when Raquel Mosquera gets married but of
cuando raquel mosquera se casa pero
course no no because when Raquel
claro no no porque cuando raquel
Mosquera gets married it has already been
mosquera se casan han pasado ya
three years
cuando son tres años
three or four years since Pedro's death
tres o cuatro años de la muerte de pedro
and three or four three or four years we
y tres o cuatro tres o cuatro años
would be talking about
estaríamos hablando del
2004-2005 which is when they get married
2004-2005 que es cuando se casan
2004-2005 the law had already been repealed for some time
2004-2005 ya la ley llevaba ya su tiempo
that is thin but the fact is that
eso está delgado pero es que además no
that article has never existed
ha existido nunca ese artículo de todo
anyway the article did not talk about what
manera el artículo no hablaba de lo que
she is saying in the
ella está diciendo en el extracto
absolute extract is that  That article has never
absoluto es que ese artículo no ha
existed in the civil code, it has
existido en el código civil nunca en el
never existed in the state.
estado nunca ha existido
If you look at the fourth section, there are
si ves la sección cuarta hay los
usufructs in many types of their fruit
usufructos en muchos tipos de su fruto
because both their fruits are their
porque los dos sus frutos es un su
enjoyment of a thing that is not yours there is
disfrutó de una cosa que no es tuya hay
more than one cattle herder
más de un pastor de ganados
their fruits are heaps but what is
sus frutos son montones pero lo que es
in article 513 which is where it tells you that is
en el artículo 513 que es donde te dice
where it tells you what reasons there are
eso es ahí donde te dice qué razones hay
to extinguish a by-product if we go down
para extinguir un subproducto si bajamos
a little bit further there are seven things for
un poquito más abajo hay siete cosas por
which it is
las que
a little bit well if you look at them none of
es un poquito pues si las ves ninguna de
them none of them is the clause that
ellas ninguna de ellas es la cláusula
says that with the thought it
que ella dice que con el pensamiento se
is with its fruit
esté con su fruto
or death by death of Raquel Mosquera
o muerte por muerte de raquel mosquera
not by expiration of the term for which it was
no por expirar el plazo por el que se
constituted or fulfillment of the
constituyó o cumplirse la condición
stated resolutory condition, I do not
resolutoria consignada esto no lo
understand this
entiendo
this is in case it had a condition in
esto es por si tenía una condición en
are its fruit of those conditionals
son un su fruto de esos condicionales
that it is better to leave its fruit for 20
que mejor le dejasen su fruto por 20
years, it is worth the reunion of the usufruct and
años vale por la reunión del usufructo y
the property in the same person because
la propiedad en una misma persona pues
from the death perhaps the
que desde se muera a lo mejor la
heir and it is hers and then of course
heredera y es de ella y entonces claro
do  yours I don't even know, even fruits of
haga suyo ya no sé incluso frutas de
them are valid for the renunciation of the
ellas vale por la renuncia del
usufructuary it is clear for the
usufructuario está claro por la pérdida
total
total de la cosa objeto de luz fruto
loss of the thing, object of light, fruit, well, it is a house and it catches fire and catches fire it is extinguished, then the house has ended, it is valid for the resolution of the right of the constituent, that is why because the right of the one who has constituted its fruit is resolved, that he has lost that right in it
que haya perdido en él ese derecho
also is not his for a thing or by
también no sea suyo por una cosa o por
prescription none is because there is a
prescripción ninguna es porque exista
marriage none we can
matrimonio ninguna la podemos
interpret it better or worse but none is
interpretar mejor o peor pero ninguna es
because he has married another relationship
porque se haya casado con otra relación
anyway those are the
de todas maneras esos son los términos
general terms of usufruct, then to
generales del usufructo vale entonces a
gratias the other those of image
graciables el otro los de imagen
we have seen before
hemos visto antes
but let's see
pero vamos viendo
the seventh section is valid 1 834 840 there
la sección séptima vale 1 834 840 ahí
are some types of usufruct by 836 it
están unos tipos de usufructo por 836
is also repealed think about all
también está derogado pensar en todos
the types of application rates
los tipos de ritmos de aplicación
depending on whether there are heirs if there are no
dependiendo si hay herederos si no hay
heirs depending on applications in
herederos dependiendo de aplicaciones en
okay
vale
1834 has been changing putting changing
1834 ha ido cambiando poniendo cambiando
more or less by the divorce law
más o menos por la ley del divorcio
then he creates in force at that time
entonces él crea vigente en ese tiempo
what I have put in capital letters
eso que tengo puesto en mayúsculas
below
debajo
is the spouse who upon death with his or her
es el cónyuge que al morir al con su
consort has not separated or
consorte no se haya separado o lo
was separated due to the fault of the deceased if he or she
estuviera por culpa del difunto si
concurs with the inheritance with children or
concurre a la herencia con hijos o
descendants you will have the right to the
descendientes tendrás derecho a los
fruits of the third destined for
frutos del tercio destinado a
a child what happens is that in this case
un hijo lo que pasa que en este caso
look at how the law was then
fíjate cómo estaba la ley entonces que
not only if they were married if he or she had been
no solamente si estaban casados si
divorced and for example it had
hubiera estado divorciado y por ejemplo
been for Pedro Carrasco because he
hubiera sido por pedro carrasco porque
would have been the one who would also have the
hubiera sido quien también tendría
right to our fruit
derecho a nuestro fruto
if they had been divorced also
si hubieran estado divorciados también
if he or she were due to the
si lo estuviera
fault of the deceased
por culpa del difunto
if it
si es que
existed for a previous year it was still even
existía por anterior año todavía incluso
legal for example if you put them
era legal por ejemplo si tú le pones los
with him to your wife who reported it was
con él a tu mujer que denunciaba era
illegal
ilegal
those laws of January 8, 2001
esas leyes del 8 enero de 2001
currently the current one has been put in place uh huh
actualmente se ha puesto la vigente ajá
changing because now it is no longer another
cambiando porque ahora ya no es otra
fault it is now simply removed if
culpa se quita ahora simplemente si
you are burdened a lot if
estás de cargas mucha tela si concurre
the inheritance concurs with children or descendants you
la herencia con hijos o descendientes
will have the right to usufruct
tendrá derecho al usufructo
or in other words Raquel Mosquera in reality
o sea que raquel mosquera en realidad
even
incluso
divorced could have had the right to so
divorciada podría haber tenido derecho a
many years of use fruit one for blame
tantos años de uso fruto uno por culpar
now well of course because it was not because
ahora bueno claro porque no era por
of Caro
culpa de caro
if it had been the group of winners
si hubiera sido el grupo de ganadores
currently you realize and no  It does not put anything about
actualmente das cuenta y no pone nada de
temporality, so by omission if it does
temporalidad por lo cual por omisión si
not put anything about the time of usufruct it is lifelong lifelong lifelong
no pone nada del tiempo del usufructo es
for that because if
vitalicio vitalicios para eso porque si
not it would put so many years I could say
no pondría tantos años lo podría decir
not to put it by omission the mass and go
no ponerlo por omisión la masa y vaya
several sentences of the supreme court
varias sentencias del tribunal supremo
in which it is clear that it is vital, it does
en el que es claro que es vital
not put temporality, the current one is now the one
no pone temporalidad el vigente es ahora
that says below 824
el que pone debajo 824
so I was looking in all
entonces yo estaba buscando en todos
these articles and the previous threads I
estos artículos y los hilos anteriores
already knew but it is not being searched
ya lo sabía pero no se está buscando a
through because civil servants have
través porque los funcionarios tenemos
that problem that when
ese problema que cuando
we say things we have to
decimos las cosas tenemos que
base the norms
fundamentar las normas
thinking where where I was looking is
pensando dónde donde buscaba está el
article 127 okay but to this day
artículo 127 vale pero al día de hoy
that does not exist in the royal decree is in
que no existe en el real decreto esté
force nor previous that there is
vigente ni anterior que exista
any article that extinguishes it suffered the
ningún artículo que extinga lo sufrió el
first one for reason of treatment of
primer al por razón de tratamiento de
cohabitation with another person
convivencia con otra persona
as there is no other civil code-
como no hay otro código civil-
substitute of the autonomous community is the one
sustitutorio de la comunidad autónoma es
that governs Madrid
el que rige el madrid
what happens is that the salt in several police
lo que pasa que la sal en varios polis
various civil
varios civiles
for example Aragon has
por ejemplo aragón tiene
civil foral of Aragon has 301 if it
de civil foral de aragón tiene el 301 si
has that clause the
tiene esa cláusula
Balearic Islands in the article  68 option
el de baleares en el artículo 68 opción
that clause but only if it is agreed upon by the
esa cláusula pero sólo si se acuerda por
state
parte del estado
in Catalonia they are in 561 found the
en cataluña están en 561 encontrado la
clause this clause that in Galicia
cláusula esta cláusula que en galicia
is in 336 in Navarre it is also in
está en 336 en navarra también está en
261 and in the Basque Country it is understood in
261 y en el país vasco se entiende en el
55 and 57 it has nothing in a purple way
55 y 57 no tiene nada de una manera
but none are valid
pero ninguno son de vigencia
well then this woman if you like
bueno pues esta mujer si te gusta el
article 127 of the old
artículo 127 de del antiguo derecho
civil law of Galicia
civil de galicia
from 4 to 95 of the game this was repealed she
del 4 al 95 de juego este fue derogado
found out
se enteró
in 2005 I think it is and there it appears
en el 2005 creo que es y ahí sí aparece
in 127 of the SAT that condition to
en el 127 de el sat esa condición a
look for the zero level as it had been
buscar el nivel cero como se había
put she has searched on google
puesto ha buscado en google
[Music]
[Música]
the usufruct is lost if you get married and
se pierde el usufructo si te casa y la
that article came up and she has gone with
salió ese artículo y ella ha ido con el
127 noted there she has read the civil code and has become
127 apuntado ahí ha leído código civil y
happier with the tapas she
se ha puesto más contenta con las tapas
has gone added for the homework done
haya ido añadido por los deberes hechos
to save me more of life the lawyer
a sálvame más de vida la abogada
is that I did not know where I could
es que yo no sabía por dónde lo podía
get it been over the weekend
sacar estado el fin de semana
in the section of  you are looking in all
en la sección de está buscando en todos
the civil codes
los códigos civiles
and it appears there in the civil code of the
y aparece ahí en el código civil de la
sight
vista
many people do that they search on google
mucha gente hace eso busca en google
and search and find a law that
y busca y encuentra una ley que le
fits them to twist the block with their
cuadra para retorcer la cuadra con su
story and out and they tell it to you like the
relato y fuera y te lo cuentan como el
captured right the last part
capturado derecho la última parte
of that I knew that the civil code
de que yo sabía que el código civil no
could not be
podía estar
all I did not know that until 200 it is one of
todos no sabía que hasta el 200 es de
those things already so that people understand
esas cosas ya para que la gente entienda
Emilio in the civil code the article that
emilio en el código civil el artículo
this lady pronounces not
eche que esta señora pronuncia no
only that he is drugged or that they
solamente que esté drogado o sea que lo
annulled it but also that the one that
anularon sino que además es que el que
existed before it was eliminated did not
existía antes de que lo eliminaran no
speak of what this lawyer was talking about
hablaba de lo que hablaba esta abogada
that the usufruct was extinguished when
de que se extinguía el usufructo cuando
when a person got married look for the
cuando una persona se casaba buscar la
review
revisión
of what she said and then it turns out
de lo que decía y entonces resulta ser
that this lady what has made you
que esta señora lo que ha hecho que
look at Emilio was eating her
mires a emilio se estaba comiendo la
head where did he get to teach at
cabeza de dónde ha sacado a enseñar en
number 127 where did you get the gentleman
el número 127 de donde sacaste al señor
is 120
es de 120
and what he has done was enter this in
y lo que ha hecho ha sido meter en
google surely we
google seguramente esto incluso lo
could even verify it in Emilio Capacite it
podríamos comprobar en emilio capacite
would not be too much of a coincidence because it would have to be
no sería mucha casualidad porque habría
put exactly exactly  she
que poner exactamente exactamente se
knows a lot of civil codes of course
sabe muchos códigos civil claro
exactly the same words she
exactamente las mismas palabras
makes the same movements as she did
hace los mismos movimientos que hiciera
but surely what she did was
pero seguramente ella lo que hizo fue
put in google
poner en google
ching
ching
for example [ __ ]
por ejemplo chingue
the usufruct
el usufructo
get married
casarse
from the tsj of Galicia probably you will
del tsj de galicia probablemente te
get a sentence from the
salga una sentencia
ts in a three-door sentence
del ts en una sentencia de tres puertas
of Galicia from 2022 look at something
de galicia de 2022 fíjate en una cosa
from 2005 and they resolved it in 2022
del 2005 y la resolvieron en el 2022 lo
what tells you that they are goals that included
que te dice que son metas que incluyeron
their fruit let's see if your god of course I'll
su fruto a ver si tu dios claro está
even tell you more there is a
incluso te digo más hay una
civil doctrine that they applied before in the tsj that
civil que aplicaban antes en el tsj que
if any son listen to me
si algún hijo escúchame
Emilio literally literally you are going to [ __ ] yourself
emilio literal literal te vas a [__]
unity and if one literally what
unidad y si uno literal lo que ha hecho
this lawyer has done is what we just did
esta abogada es lo que acabamos de hacer
listen to me it's not a joke I have put look what I am
escúchame no es coña he puesto mira lo
going to share so that
que voy a compartir para que todo el
everyone can see it or rather what this
mundo lo vea o sea lo que ha hecho esta
lawyer has done
abogada
to go with her homework done to the
para ir con los deberes hechos al debate
Rocío debate okay it was to
de rociíto vale
write in google
ha sido escribir en google se extingue
the usufruct is extinguished Alcázar okay I
el usufructo alcázar se vale yo me
imagine that with the idea Emilio of searching
imagino que con la idea emilio de buscar
something that fits with something that her
algo que le cuadre con algo que sus
bosses are going to prove okay then she
jefes vayan a probar vale entonces ella
has taken and has written to see, to see, to see
ha cogido y ha escrito a ver a ver a ver
when instead of reading the
cuando sea en vez de leerse los códigos
civil codes as facts a thousand and so on she has said
civiles como hechos mil y demás ha dicho
for what she looks for that directly and if
por lo busca que directamente y si me
a law of Mexico comes out to take it by the
sale una ley de méxico para tomar por
ass the law of Mexico does not extinguish
culo la ley de mexico no se extingue
illusion fruit when getting married
ilusión fruto al casarse
this first jurisprudential web page has come out
le ha salido esta primera página web
Emilio and
jurisprudente se ha metido emilio y
Gloria have gotten into it demented
gloria demente
and you literally get out of the
y literalmente te sales de la
update of 2001 when the
actualización del 2001 cuando el
counselor has come out the law
conseller ha salido la ley
the civil law comes
la ley civil llega
from 95
desde el 95
nap of 95 and also
siesta del 95 y además
because of the new one of 2006 valid until
por la nueva del 2006 vigente hasta el
2005 it was not in force when Pedro
2005 no estaba vigente cuando pedro
Carrasco but to have
carrasco pero tener de aplicación
that application applied to the territory of
esa aplicación para el territorio de
Galicia to have come out of Santiago de
galicia haber salido de santiago de
Compostela
compostela
Galicia you
galicia
have to throw it out way they fall against the
hay que echarla way caen contra la
lawyer
abogada
of course she has gone to the superior court of
claro se ha ido al tribunal superior de
justice of Galicia and they have against that
justicia de galicia y se han contra esa
law
ley
oh I die
ay me muero
article 127 of 1995 is worth the
el artículo 127 de 1995 vale el
usufruct of  widowhood is screwed by the
usufructo de viudedad se chingue por el
new marriage of the
nuevo matrimonio de los del
usufructuary unless there is an agreement or provision
usufructuario salvo pacto o disposición
against the accident, they were agreed upon and
contra el siniestro quedaron pacto y
enjoyed that this law
disfrutase que esta ley
in addition to this tape not at that
además de que esta cinta no en ese
time
tiempo
in 2001
en el 2001
we are talking about Raquel Mosquera
estamos hablando de que raquel mosquera
getting married 34 years later or 5 to
se casa 34 años después o 5 hasta la
date it was three years not 2001
fecha eran tres años no 2001
of course but they give her six years
claro pero ellas a ella le dan seis años
and she claims with Rocío six years and she had
y afirma con la rociíto seis años y le
three left when it is not that she gets married
quedaban tres cuando no es que se case
that she went to live it is not that she is lacking
que se fue a vivir no es que se carezca
either then then if then that law
tampoco luego luego si luego esa ley le
has continued to maintain her in 236 of 2006
ha seguido manteniendo en el 236 de 2006
if you are 16
si tienes 16
that if it is a little lower if you do not
que si está un poquito más abajo si no
get them a little lower in that
les logras un poquito más abajo en esa
same one it is both if it is in 2006
misma es tanto si está en el 2006
the card on this part applies in
la tarjeta de esta parte aplica en
Galicia Galicia territorial its
galicia galicia territoriales su código
civil code and in addition there are even some that
civil y además incluso hay algunos que
have a different
tienen un sufrido diferente
universal suffering since everything is clear with
universal ya que se queda todo claro con
those clauses but they remain not in
esas cláusulas pero se quedan no en
thirds and not all
tercios y no todo
militia the same
milicia lo mismo
if they work or in other words manipulate are against
si trabajan o sea manipulan sean contra
the jce has put so  happy afterward
la jce ha puesto tan contentos después
well I die because there are people who watch
bueno me muero porque hay gente que ve
Sálvame or these programs it's not a
sálvame o estos programas no es una
lawyer talking to us making a fallacy
abogada hablándonos haciendo una falacia
of authority that is called that it is not one it
de autoridad que se llama eso no es una
is a fallacy of authority in the
es una falacia de autoridad en el
sense that people give her
sentido de que la gente le da
credibility for the simple fact that she
credibilidad por el simple hecho de que
is telling you that she is a lawyer she
te está diciendo que ella es abogada
uses the term lawyer and people
utiliza el término abogada y la gente te
are telling you
lo está diciendo
mother I like
madre me gusta
Emilio brutal and when you come again
emilio brutal y cuando vienes otra vez
well if you want after
bueno si quieres a continuación del pozo
yesterday's well I'll tell you something
de ayer te cuento algo
clear what a
claro
change of the well when he brought up the subject
vaya cambio del pozo cuando sacó el tema
of the Chilean goalkeeper's well because I was not
del pozo de la portera chilena porque no
going to understand it I say it
lo iba a entender lo digo
with the passage of the value of the property but
con el paso del valor de la finca pero
we see the well on the ownership of
vemos el pozo sobre la propiedad
the well what happens when you have a
del pozo qué pasa cuando tienes un
will
testamento
all the laws everything I mean all the law
todas las leyes todo digo toda la ley
this all the assets that you have because you
esto todos los bienes que tienes porque
cannot go changing them over time
no puedes ir cambiando durante el tiempo
only put the assets that you
solamente poner los bienes que se
want to keep to someone for example in this one
quieran quedar a alguien por ejemplo en
's property normally that is what
finca de éste normalmente eso lo que
puts the
pone
warming I don't know what is
al calentamiento no sé que tenga
planned the day that you are going to die it is
planeado el día que te va a morir está
complicated you do not change it every
complicado no lo vas cambiando todos los
day so well if it is established
días entonces bueno si está fincada
safe position
puesto seguro
but also not the rest is generic what
pero además no lo demás es genérico que
happens you can stay  a national asset
pasa tú te puedes quedar un bien
you can keep an asset out for whatever reason
tú te puedes quedar un bien fuera por lo
because the only thing you have in the
que sea porque sólo tengas en el
land registry is that it is not registered
catastro no tenga registro
then nothing happens you go back to the
entonces no pasa nada tú vuelves al
notary and it is an
notario y hace es una decisión de
inheritance decision and that addition of inheritance is
herencia y esa adición de herencia está
in the same terms in which it exists
en los mismos términos en la que existe
at the time in the inheritance
en su momento en la herencia
logically the well as it was not in the
lógicamente el pozo como no estaba en el
hereditary estate
caudal hereditario
this
esto termina de arrancar el 19 por
ends up tearing off the 19 percent 33 of its fruit for which the bear is if he sold it if he sold it Rocío Carrasco sold it fraudulently because that well also had to have been signed for him to Mosquera or have liquidated the usufruct at the time but now that
usufructo en su momento pero ahora que
Mosquera had to have signed the well
mosquera tenía que haber firmado el pozo
just as it has already
igual que ya ha
prescribed
prescrito
in addition he would buy it in the land registry however
además lo compraría en el catastro como
but the well
fuera pero el pozo
in a way compadre in a plan that they do not have a
de manera compadre en plan que no tienen
chair anywhere that most
cátedra en ninguna parte que lo más
likely also I tell you the wells
probable también te digo los pozos
have to be
tienen que son son concesiones
administrative concessions they have an exploitation
administrativas tienen una explotación
that has to be associated with some
que tiene que estar asociada alguna
property it can no longer be like call my
finca ya no puede estar en plan llama mi
brother-in-law bricklayer that pipe machine
cuñado albañil esa máquina de tubería
has to ask permission from the
tiene que pedir permiso a la
hydrographic confederation of the
confederación hidrográfica del
Guadalquivir
guadalquivir
the city council
el ayuntamiento
if it has a Celtic natural park if it has
si tiene parque natural celta si tiene
any administration they have to make
alguna administración tienen que hacer
sectoral reports you have to say
informes sectoriales tienes que decir
exactly how much water you are going to extract from
exactamente cuánto agua vas a sacar de
granting a 100-year concession from the
dar una concesión a 100 años de la
autonomous community and in addition they do
comunidad autónoma y además
not give another nearby connection s
no dan otra conexión cercana s
how many kilometers the
cuántos kilómetros
same as if I
igual que igual que
could see it
si lo podía ver
[Music] exactly I was going to
[Música]
mention the
exactamente te iba a mencionar el
belt imagine the center to me it is
cinturón imagínate el centro me lo mí es
exactly the same just as she
exactamente lo mismo igual que ella no
cannot mention the belt the belt
puede mencionar el cinturón el cinturón
is already where it is it is total although or rather
ya está donde está es total aunque o sea
although Rocío
aunque aunque tuviera la razón rocío
Carrasco was right that the belt
carrasco en que el cinturón le
belonged to her because at the time they
pertenecía a ella porque en su día la
fought even if she was right it would already
pelearon aunque tuviera la razón ya
be prescribed why are we
estaría prescrito por qué estamos
talking
hablando
and what they signed in the agreement that they
y lo que firmaron en el acuerdo que lo
signed what it was
firmaron lo que era
although the historical one
aunque el histórico
not either
no tampoco
because in addition she herself recognized
porque además ella misma reconoció
according to her of course we have to
según ella claro que no lo tenemos que
believe it according to her she did not know the well to
creer según ella el pozo no lo conocía a
anyone, I
nadie
mean neither she nor her mother had
o sea ni ella ni su madre se la había
ever mentioned it to her she is
mencionado nunca ella se lleva la
surprised that she has a well when the
sorpresa de que tiene un pozo cuando el
man gets in touch with her
hombre se pone en contacto con ella
then then in some way there
entonces entonces de alguna manera ahí
she is acknowledging that with the
ella está reconociendo que con el pozo
porn well she is reproducing
del porno de ella está reproduciendo
reported from her well and she is
reportados de ella bueno y está
recognizing that the well is
reconociendo que el pozo está la
Pedro Carrasco's inheritance then as
herencia de pedro carrasco entonces como
she Pedro Carrasco's inheritance
ella la herencia de pedro carrasco
dedicated made a function having
dedicaron hecho una función haberse
sat down with Raquel Mosquera having taken
sentado con raquel mosquera haber cogido
the mount of the day
el monte del día
23 percent of its fruit of the well
23 por ciento de su fruto del pozo
even if it was 300 euros and then when they
aunque fueran 300 euros y luego cuando
had sold it to her she had to have
lo hubieran vendido a la tenía que haber
signed both because it is a condominium
firmado las dos porque es un condominio
as it was not
como no se
divided in the inheritance you are imparting it is
partió en la herencia estás impartir es
a condominium
un condominio
then husband could not sell it and
entonces esposo no lo podía vendidos y
the signature of the we want
la firma de la queremos
well removing all the others all
bien quitando todas las demás todos
all the other stories only
todas las demás historias solamente se
signed up then I will talk to them if tomorrow
apuntó luego los voy a hablar si mañana
you come and tell us about the census
te vienes y nos cuenta lo del padrón
okay that people are seeing them the
vale que los está viendo la gente el
pimp of course now it will not
chapero por supuesto ahora no
be a regulator
va a ser de regulador
tomorrow we talk
mañana hablamos
about a
de un
very good very good I this
buenísimo buenísimas yo este fin de
weekend have a croquette I stayed but
semana tiene una croqueta me quede pero
that you in the end it turned out better without us having done it
que tú al final salió mejor sin que lo
if it is
si
worth today a hug from Emilio what a
vale hoy un abrazo de emilio vaya
machine you have left us you always
máquina que nos has dejado siempre los
leave them stunned you always leave them in
dejas embobados siempre los dejas de
shock a hug
piedra un abrazo
come on see you later
venga hasta luego
how have you been
como os habéis quedado
as you know that given  The
como sabéis que dado
lawyer's story is great, kid. The lawyer's
buenísimo lo de la abogada chaval
story is great, Google's lawyer's story is
buenísimo lo de la abogada de google
family is great, great.
familia buenísimo buenísimo
[Music]
[Música]